KHAI NGUYEN

khaiatwork@gmail.com | github.com/khaister

A Senior Software Engineer with 8+ years in object-oriented software engineering, applied to the creation of complex software systems and tackling technical challenges; strengths in working collaboratively with technical and business teams to produce outstanding software products from design to launch.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer at blinkhealth.com from MAR 2022 to PRESENT

- Build the core Web API backend service for managing prescriptions
- Integrate a Django RESTful web API into the proprietary pharmacy software for insurance eligibility and claim purposes
- Build software on top of an automation workflow engine (Camunda Platform) to integrate with external provider for drug prescription data flow according to business requirements

Senior Software Engineer at apartments.com from AUG 2019 to MAR 2022

- Designed and implement Messaging system using RESTful Web API and background service components, deployed to AWS-hosted VPC
- Built a web service from scratch to support Online Tour Scheduling functionalities for multi-family communities
- On-boarded new team members onto various projects within Apartments.com codebase
- Coached/transferred knowledge to junior developers on software engineering in general, Apartments.com domain knowledge, and development process
- Led technical interviews during hiring process to evaluate potential candidates for team
- Led/collaborated with team members at all seniority levels and coordinated with stakeholders to unblock process and ensure features were delivered as specified and in a timely manner

Software Development Engineer at quickbridge.com from OCT 2018 to JUL 2019

- Built & maintained middle-tier web services using the latest ASP.NET Framework for sending SMS messages via Twilio API within a 3-month turnaround time
- Designed & implemented the SMS UI/UX using Angular 4 for internal CRM web application

Software Engineer at cudirect.com from JUN 2015 to SEP 2018

- Implemented features for a WPF application, along with the backend Web API, for loan & account management purposes
- Oversaw version control system migration from TFVC to Git repositories, including training 20 team members & promoting best practices, effectively increased development velocity and collaboration across 5 teams
- Led release deployment effort by coordinating teams to finalize software components for production release

SKILLS

- Backend Django, Python, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MySQL, REST APIs, .NET Core/C#
- Cloud AWS (ECS, Lambda, SNS, SQS, DynamoDB)
- Frontend TypeScript/JavaScript, React, Styled Components
- DevOps macOS, CI/CD, Git, GitHub Actions, Docker, Bash, Agile

EDUCATION

B.Sc. cum laude in Biochemistry with Computer Science

California State University, Long Beach (2015)